YOGENDRA PRATAP

Mobile: 91-9012227865,91-9868654298

yogendra.pundir@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Microsoft certified in .NET, MVC and SQL Server and having total 9.8 Years of experience with 8.8 years in .NET Technologies in development, testing and implementation of software projects, have a sound knowledge of Software Development Life Cycle.

<u>Expertise Area</u>: ASP.Net, C#,MVC,WebAPI,Web Services, XML,XSLT, ADO.Net, SQL Server, LINQ TO SQL, SSRS, SSIS, WCF, Crystal Report, Role Based Security, TFS Server, Dev Express Controls, Telerik Controls, Expert in Window Application and Web Application and in Dot Net Nuke, LINQ TO Entity, JQuery Code First, Json, LightSwitch, WCF RIA Service, AngularJS, KendoUI.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Presently working as Technical Leader in KNY Informatics since May 2015 to Till Date.

Worked as **Technical Consultant in Crowe Horwath India Private Limited** since October 2013 to May 2015.

Worked as Senior Software Engineer in I2K2 Networks PVT Ltd, Client (General Informatics USA). Noida since January 2009 to October 2013.

Worked as **Senior Software Engineer in ENETSYS WEB SOLUTIONS Pvt.** Ltd.Delhi.since June 2008 to Dec 2008.

Worked as **Software Developer in MCL Systems Ltd.** Delhi since June 2007 to June 2008.

Worked as a **Software Programmer in eLanzer Solutions** Delhi since January 2006 to May 2007.

EDUCATION

M.Tech (I.T) from AAI Deemed University Allahabad in 2005.

PGDCA from Punjab Technical University Jalandhar in 2002

M.Sc (Maths) from C.C.S University Meerut in 2000.

B.Sc (PCM) from C.C.S University Meerut in 1998.

SKILL SET

Languages : C#, MVC 5, VB.NET, ASP.NET (2.0, 3.5, 4.0, 4.5, 4.5.1),

Technology : .NET(4.5.1,4.5,3.5/2.0),MVC 5, AngularJS, Web Service,
Web API, WCF, Ajax, Jquery, Ling to SQL, Ling To Entity,

Entity Framework Code First, Dot Net Nuke, LightSwitch.

RDBMS Tools : MS SQL Serve2005-2008, ORACL, SSRS Operating Systems : Windows 2000/XP.Vista, Windows 7

Reporting tool: Crystal Report, SSRS.

Third Party Tools: DevExpress, Component one Conrols, Telerik Controls.

Project name : Complete Real Estate Solutions(C-RES).

Role : Tech Lead (Requirement Gathering, Coding and Team Handling)

Environment : MVC5, Web API, AngularJs, C#, SQL Server 2012, Entity Framework Code First, Kendo UI, JQuery, SSIS, SSRS.

Description : This is a web portal for all the real estate professionals. There are separate role for each professional. Admin or back office can assign multiple roles for user. Portal enables users to introduce their property for sale, rent, and buy online, to the market. Users have their own portfolio, which is assigned to them at the first time registration time. This service allows each user to specify their property information and select an agent or agents.

Consumer side allows new users to begin with creation of a portfolio and set up a Username and Password by registering. Users, then, are lead to step through the process such as entering their property s detail, receive information of the identical sales. User can search properties for buy and rent in selected area, location.

Modules are:-

- 1. Bye
- 2. Resale
- 3. Projects
- 4. Rent
- 5. Commercial
- 6. Dealers
- 7. Deals

Project name : C-TRAC

Role : Technical Consultant (Requirements Gathering, Analysis,

Coding and Team Handling)

Environment: MVC 5, AngularJs, ASP.Net 4.5.1 C#, SQL Server 2012,

Entity Framework Code First, Kendo UI, JQuery, Web API.

Description : The Only IRS-Approved Software Developed by Tax Exempt Specialists If yours is like most tax-exempt organization, you face significant information-gathering, project management, and educational efforts related to tax compliance requirements. Tax-exempt specialists understand these challenges and have developed C-TRAC to help you accurately complete forms and schedules in less time, without straining internal resources.

Since the launch of first version of C-TRAC in 2008, IT team continued to invest in the solution, listening closely to users. Version 7.0 released in March 2015.

Features of the C-TRAC

Web-Based, IRS-Approved, Easy to Use - Supports IRS forms 990 and 990T, extensions, and international disclosures (926, 8865, etc.).

Automated Conflict-of-Interest Questionnaires - Streamlines communication and is fully customizable.

Alternative Investment Module - Aggregates K-1 data and determines federal, state, and international reporting responsibilities.

 $\begin{tabular}{ll} \textbf{Master Compensation Module} &- Simplifies compensation through enterprise wide reporting. \end{tabular}$

Master Schedule R - Manages transfers between and among related organizations. State Module - Completes all state income and attorney general filings and streamlines extensions and estimates.

Project name : R&D Navigator

Role : Technical Consultant (Requirements Gathering, Analysis and

Coding Team Handling)

Environment : ASP.Net 4.5, MVC 4, C#, SQL Server 2008, Entity Framework

Code First, SSIS, SSRS, Telerik Controls, Jquery, WCF.

Crowe R&D Navigator helps automate burdensome, time consuming and nonviable-added activities long associated with claiming federal and state research and development (R&D) tax credits. This innovative and fresh solution is flexible, intuitive, and can be scaled and adapted based on each taxpayer's unique facts and circumstances. Crowe R&D Navigator includes on-the-fly qualifying research expenditure and credit calculations, real-time progress and analytical reporting on a number of levels and sub levels, and customized reporting schedules and work papers relevant to your business. Developed by Crowe Horwath LLP R&D specialists, this proprietary software solution leverages the deep insight of seasoned and dedicated R&D professionals with experience across a wide variety of industries.

Project : PayAway (https://live.payaway.net).

Client : General Informatics (USA)

Team Size : 12

Duration : Jan 2009 To Feb 2012.

Modules are

1.Company Module

2.Plan Module

3. Validation Module (Lexis Nexis, Epicware, Positive, Negative, Fraud)

4.Roles and Security

5.ACH Implementation (Prenotification , Origination , Dishonour)

6. Return code handling

7.Reports

Description of the project: The PayAway™ is a web-enabled alternative payment software solution and settlement service. The first of its kind payment solution providing purchasing power to those customers with no credit, thin credit or just plain credit challenged. Our innovative payment solutions create opportunities for any big ticket retailers to deliver incremental sales on a "Guaranteed" Breakeven Profit or Better Basis. The PayAway™ system allows the customer to buy the products and services that customer wants by paying for them through manageable monthly payments .Payment are based on company policy all debit and credit transaction maintain by ACH after down payments customer can pick merchandise. Even and uneven exchange facility also provide according to company policy. Plan also modify according to various company rules. There are plans available for the customers to pay in installments, merchandise of specific companies is available for the customer to buy it through the retailers shops and installment plan can be generated for it. This project involved the ACH transaction, and is focused mainly for the US market, This project maintains the status of the customers/Searching of customer details. This project handle ACH(American Clearing House) transactions, it also involves generation of various reports related to the transactions and customer transactions reports application use very tight security using membership user can take action According to role.

Highlights: Use of Linq to SQL, Generics collections, Javascript, Stored Procedure,

Function, SSRS,SSIS,WCF,XML, ASP.NET Memberships Providers, 3rd party

Devexpress tools \nSoftware component for ACH Converter.

Designation: Senior Software Engineer

Platform: Asp.net 3.5 ,C#.net ,SQL Server 2008, JavaScript, Ajax, Devexpress tool.

Project name : EBRDA (East Baton Rouge District Attorney).

Organization: I2K2 Networks Client(East Baton Rouge Traffic Department).

Team Size : 2

Role : Team Leader

Technologies Used .NET 4.5, LightSwitch, DevExpress Controls, SSRS, SSIS, SQL Server

2008. Component one Conrols, WCF Ria Service. Odata Service.

Modules are

1.Traffic Ticket Module

2.Court Modume.

3.PTI Module.

4. Report Module.

5. Prosecutor Module.

6.Traffic Charge Module.

7.Judge Module.

Project name : Family and Youth Service Department of Louisiana State(USA).

Organization : I2K2 Networks Client(FYSC).

Team Size : 2

Role : Team Leader

Technologies Used : .NET 4.5, LightSwitch, DevExpress Controls, SSRS, SSIS , SQL Server

2008 Tools, Component one Conrols, WCFRiaService. Odata

Service.

Modules are

1.Information Module.

2.Security Mudule.

3. Service Provider Module.

4.Report Module.
5.Service Module.

Project name : www.ebrso.org.

Organization : I2K2 Networks Client (East Baton Rouge Parish).

Team Size : 2

Role : SSE

Technologies Used: DOTNET Nuke, SQL Server 2008, SSRS, SSIS.

Modules are 1. Tickets. 2. Taxes.

3. Foreclosures.

4. InmateList.

WarrentList.

6. Careers.

Project Title: Training Observation

Technology: Asp.Net 3.5, C#, SQL Server, Ajax, Jquery, Linq to Entity

SSRS, SSIS.

Team Size: 2

Role: Coding, Interaction with Client, Deployment, Unit Testing.

Client: General Informatics.

Modules are

1. Supervisor module.

2.FTO Module

3. Trainee Module

4.Coordinator Module

5. Report ans performance module.

<u>Description of the project</u>: The observation is a web-enabled alternative software solution there are total 3 phase of training after every phase the performance report submit by FTO to supervisor then supervisor approve or disapprove the performance report if report approve then report submit to coordinator otherwise trainee need to participate in same training session again.

Project Title:

Deltek.

Technology: .Net 3.5, C#, SQL Server, SSRS 2005

Team Size: 4

Role: Coding, Interaction with Client, Unit Testing.

Client: General Informatics, USA

Project description -:

<u>Custom Proposal Module 1.Deltek</u> is Window based application to create custom proposal user can create custom proposal to insert data dynamically user entered data updated in word file then user can save proposal, proposal data saved as XML in database when user come next time user can create proposal from existing or can create new or update existing proposal.

Reports Module 2. Various report are created using SSRS 2005 and It has an utility "Report Administration" that is used to load custom reports built reports(.rdl) in BIDS 2005. One can create report using deltek database according to report requirement and then make a setup that will copy that report file to specific directory of deltek application on server, and then report can be loaded through its utility.

Project Title: Online Ticketing System

Technology: .NET (3.5),C#, SQL-Server 2008 ,SSRS,SSIS.

Team Size: 3

Duration: 6 Months

Role: Senior Software Developer
Client: General Informatics, USA

Project description -:

This is a window based application. The application objective is to keep data of tickets that is assigned to any deputy for invalid parking, uniform summons and warning according to traffic rules. Application architecture had to change and it has been re-architectured using web services.

Project Title: Email Save.

Technology: .Net 3.5, C#, SQL Server, Outlook Add Ins,WCF.

Team Size: 4

Role: Coding, Interaction with Client, Unit Testing.

Client: General Informatics, USA

Project description -:

<u>Email Save</u> is Window based application to save outlook emails, a setup need to be install on user system then user can save their email manually or automatically.

When user receive, send or try to delete a email a popup window open do you want to save this email when user click ok button a window form load user need to select the related project and click save button if related path exist then email save at related path, if user saving email first time using selected project then a popup window open path does not exist please save manually then browser window open to choose path here user need to select

path and press ok button to save email at user system or at network and path save in database for future use then next time email will save automatically.

Name and URL : IFC (cricket.indianfantasyleague.com)

Technology used: asp.net 2.0, sqlserver 2005, JavaScript, Ajax.

Duration : 6 Month.
Team size : 6
Description:

There are two sections in this project:

USER SECTION: IFC is the most comprehensive fantasy cricket game available Online! You can create your own team that plays and scores for you. You are the Owner, selector and manager. New User: Signup to play all you have to do is to Register yourself using a valid email id. You get to name your team. Your team will Even get its own page where others can come and watch your team's performance. At the end of each match day, the scores for your players and team will be updated Within a short time. Ranks for top registered teams will also be displayed. Create Your Match timetables and results it shows the timetables of all Portfolio such as initial credits, initial value, current value, balance credits, team net Worth, and increase/decrease in value of my team, credits earned or spent. Manage My team players once you have successfully registered, you can go right ahead and Create your very their own own IFC team and take on the International Game. You will be given an extensive players list to select your 16 member fantasy teams at Team. Manage my playing 11 from your Fantasy Team of 16, as a team have to select a Playing XI before the start of the matches. Remember, only the players in your Playing XI will score points for you. Your current selection will be your default Selection, Remember to regularly update your Playing XI based on the upcoming Matches. If you and will be carried forward to upcoming matches till the time you decide to make changes, and then your new selection will become your default Playing XI. Invite friends All you have to do is invite your friends to join in the cricketing Bonanza, and you could earn up to 20 credits.

FAO

Here is a list of FAQs you might find handy. Just in case your query is still unanswered please contact us at feedback@cricket.indianfantasyleague.com to give us your feedback.

ADMIN SECTION:

In this section there is a GUI by which admin user can feed the scores for every Player of user's team.

Project name : No Fuss Trade
Organization : eLanzer Solutions.

Team Size : 5

Role : Team Member

Technologies Used: C# 2.0, ASP.Net 2.0, ADO.Net 2.0, SQL-Server 2K5.

Description : This Website has feature of rich portal for b2b & b2c trade in United Kingdom. This portal is unique in terms of services it offers: It has option to choose from services and purchase of products. The portal will have companies listing in various sub categories for major categories like: Gift Items, Cheese, Wine and Transportation for the companies as well as the visitors of UK. The portal will provide the services to the companies in terms of business leads (trade leads) by making advertisement of the companies in various

related segments & the companies will provide annual membership fee in lieu of the above services.

The portal includes modules like:

- Company Registration Module
- Transportation Module
- Advertisement Module
- Company Search Module
- Products Search from various categories
- Purchase Products
- Avail Services from Companies
- Payment Module For both Visitors as well as Companies (Via Payment Gateway)
 Securing Transactions using SSL

Project name : http://support.cadebill.com

Organization: MCL Systems.

Team Size : 3

Role : Team Member

Technologies Used: C# 2.0, ASP.Net 2.0, ADO.Net 2.0, SQL-Server 2K5.

Description : Cadebill Support is basically support side of Cadebill. It provides a web interface to the customers with a secure private login and password. Customers can self service their accounts, user can resolve their issues online here they can post their bugs, suggestion etc with the help of message and screen shots (attachments). And later he can view the solution given by the technical team. It has automated email facility to inform both of internal and external users regarding the activity being performed there

Project name : Enterprise Portal

Organization : MCL System Ltd.

Team Size :

Role : Team Member

Technologies Used : ASP.NET, C# and SQL Server 2000

Description : Enterprise portal is one of the portal which

Serves for customers to purchase any types of goods through online. Enterprise

Portal is One of the portal which is useful for organizations to sell any types of goods through Online. Finally it is a bridge for venders and customers and easy goods through Online. Finally it is a bridge for venders and customers and easy for their transactions

Interests and activities

- i) Software development and design
- ii) Willingness to learn and exploring things
- iii) Reading books.

Personal Information

Father's Name : Sh. Bhagirath Singh
Date of Birth : 05-02-1977
Nationality : Indian
Passport No : G6098590

Sex Male Marital status Married

42/6A, West Vinod Nagar, Delhi-110092 English, Hindi Address

Language known

Place: New Delhi (Yogendra Pratap)

Date:

